DIAN US SUQLAIN

241-A Muslim town, Lahore · 0303 4125027 dianussuqlain1@gmail.com

As a teenager I am very enthusiastic and conscious towards achieving my goal in life which is to become a software engineer. To bring some change in life and to prove that success can only be achieved by hard work.

During my degree, I have developed an excellent eye for detail due to the heavy demands of assignments and research. As a result, I am also able to work under pressure.

EXPERIENCE

10TH JULY, 2019 – 30TH AUGUST, 2019 INTERN, PACKAGES LIMITED

Placed as a project Intern under IT department and had to make several projects out of which, the major project was related to Machine Learning.

6TH JUNE, 2018 – 10TH SEPTEMBER, 2018 INTERN, INOVEDIA (SOFTWARE HOUSE)

Over the course period of 3 months, I am confident that I can easily build a website using Bootstrap and JavaScript, I have not completely perfected my skills in them but as far as I have learnt in 3 months, I can make good looking and attractive websites and their contents.

12th JULY, 2017—AUGUST, 2017INTERNSHIP, PCYO (PAKISTAN CRESCENT YOUTH ORGANIZATION)

Worked with PCYO for one month to collect funds for the poor children in Lahore. Certificate for brand ambassadorship given by Pakistan Crescent Youth Organization

EDUCATION

OCTOBER 2017 TO 2021

BS SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF MANAGEMENT & TECHNOLOGY

By the grace of Allah Almighty, I have completed 4 semesters in UMT and achieving a CGPA of 3.31. Certificate in organizing an event on better English communication skills in UMT. Also being the president of Computer Science Society of the current year i.e. 2019-2020.

SEPTEMBER 2015 TO 2017

INTERMEDIATE ICS (PHYSICS), PUNJAB GROUP OF COLLEGES

Got 71% marks by the end of second year in Punjab College. Participated in science exhibition contest in first year.

2005 TO AUGUST 2015

OLEVELS (COMPUTER SCINCE), ST. PETER'S HIGH SCHOOL

78.75% marks by the end of school year in O'Level's participated in many events, games and debates such as: organized and participated in debating competitions. Participated and organized annual sports gala.

Played the following:

- -Athletics
- -Basketball
- -Football
- -Cricket
- -Snooker
- -Participated in Annual Christmas Play

SKILLS

- C++ PROGRAMMING
- JAVA LANGUAGE
- OOP
- Data Structures and Algorithms

- HTML5
- CSS 3
- Java Script
- GOOD IN HANDLING MS OFFICE
- C# .NET

ACTIVITIES

Certificate of participation in annual Science Exhibition contest in Punjab College in 2016.

Certificate of participation in Toyota dream car competition in 2014

Participated in the 8th Dawn International Spelling Bee in 2012.

Participated in International Kangaroo Math Competition in the year 2008.

Certificate awarded for obtaining 7th position in Spoken English course in Children's Library Complex in 2008.

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Football Snooker Table Tennis Basketball Programming Web Developing